Guide to the Joseph Brodsky Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Interviews and Speeches, 1974-1996; Series III; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  - Speeches
    Consist of notes and drafts unless otherwise noted.
    - Lecture in Colorado, 1975 (Box 123, Folder 2763)
    - "Language as otherland," delivered at Amherst College and Hunter College, 1976 (Box 123, Folder 2764-2765)
    - Presentation of Czesław Miłosz to the Neustadt Prize Jury, draft and printed version, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 2766)
    - Introduction of Czesław Miłosz, 1979? (Box 123, Folder 2767)
    - Introduction of Anthony Hecht, draft and printed version, 1981 (Box 123, Folder 2768-2769)
    - Address at Solidarity Town Hall, 1982? (Box 123, Folder 2770)
    - Lecture on Marina Tsvetaeva at Yale University, 1984 (Box 123, Folder 2771)
    - Memorial for Carl Proffer, 1984 (Box 123, Folder 2772-2773)
    - Introduction of Derek Walcott, 1986 (Box 123, Folder 2774)
    - Introduction of Howard Moss, 1986 (Box 123, Folder 2775)
    - Introduction of Mark Strand
      - English language version, drafts and printed version, 1986 (Box 123, Folder 2776-2777)
      - Russian translation by Elena Kasatkina, proof, 1996 (Box 123, Folder 2778-2779)
    - Tanner lecture on human values, 1987 (Box 123, Folder 2780)
      See also: Series II, Writings -- Writings of Others -- Strand, Mark
    - Nobel prize acceptance speech, English translation by Barry Rubin, printed version, 1984-1988 (Box 123, Folder 2781-2783)
      Brodsky's Nobel lecture is filed in Series II, Writings -- Prose -- Individual Prose Writings -- "Litsa neobshchim vyrazhen'em" (Nobel lecture)
    - Mount Holyoke College commencement address, 1988 (Box 123, Folder 2784)
    - New York Public library lecture, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 2785-2786)
    - On Danilo Kiš, 1991 (Box 123, Folder 2787)
    - Introduction of Czesław Miłosz and Paul Muldoon at the Library of Congress, 1991 or 1992 (Box 123, Folder 2788)
    - Introduction of Lee Gerlach and Peter Viereck at the Library of Congress, 1991 or 1992 (Box 123, Folder 2789)
    - Introduction of Linda Gregg and Mary Jo Salter at the Library of Congress, 1991 or 1992 (Box 123, Folder 2790)
    - Introduction of Mahon and Zagaievskii at the Library of Congress, 1991 or 1992 (Box 124, Folder 2791)
    - Nobel symposium speech, 1991-1992 (Box 124, Folder 2792-2793)
    - University of Katowice honorary degree acceptance speech
      - English language version, 1993 (Box 124, Folder 2794-2796)
      - Polish language translation by Renata Gorczyńska, 1993 (Box 124, Folder 2797)
    - "Ves'ma Angliiskoe Meropriiatie" (on Mandelshtam), 1994 (Box 124, Folder 2798-2799)
    - Introduction to a radio broadcast of Brodsky reciting poetry, undated (Box 124, Folder 2800)
- Teaching Material and Student Papers, 1973-1995; Series IV; 2.5; (7 boxes)
  Access to teaching evaluations, student records and student papers is restricted until 2071.
  Student Papers are arranged alphabetically by name of student.
  Teaching material includes background material and documents associated with courses Brodsky taught, including syllabi, course descriptions, and photocopies of curricular material. The papers are not comprehensive enough or of sufficient quantity to thoroughly document Brodsky's teaching activity. Student papers consists of papers written by students for Brodsky's courses at Columbia, Mount Holyoke and elsewhere.
  - Notes and background material, 1973-1990, undated (Box 125, Folder 2801-2815)
    Consists of photocopies of curricular material from Brodsky's courses. Includes material sent from Anna Priddy (a former Mount Holyoke student) to Ann Kjellberg and a reading packet from a course taught by Mark Strand in 1987.
  - Notes and background material, 1973-1990, undated (Box 126, Folder 2816)
  - Syllabi and reading lists, 1984, undated (Box 126, Folder 2817-2822)
    Includes syllabi for courses taught by Peter Viereck and others.
  - Assignments, undated (Box 126, Folder 2823-2824)
  - Teaching evaluations, 1988-1993 (Box 127, Folder 2825)
  - Student records, 1988-1995 (Box 127, Folder 2826-2830)
  - Student Papers
    Arranged alphabetically by name of student.
    - "A"-"D", 1981-1995, undated (Box 128, Folder 2831-2869)
    - "E"-"Mc", 1981-1995, undated (Box 129, Folder 2870-2917)
    - "Mi"-"W", 1980-1995, undated (Box 130, Folder 2918-2959)
    - "Y," unidentified, 1994, undated (Box 131, Folder 2960-2967)
- Personal papers, 1961-2000; Series V; 3.96; (10 boxes)
  The Series is organized by type of material and arranged chronologically therein where possible.
  Certificates, diplomas and honorary medals document the honorary degrees Brodsky received from several institutions. Brodsky's Nobel Medal is not present in the collection. Drawings by Brodsky are sketches in pen and ink and include self-portraits, portraits of others and allegorical scenes. Calendars and date books contain informal daily notes, phone numbers, addresses and information about travel itineraries and appointments. Medical papers include medical bills and records. Financial papers include bills, bank records and receipts. Legal papers include documentation of Brodsky's emigration and of his efforts to assist other emigres (including his efforts to obtain a visa for his parents to visit the United States). Inscriptions consist of photocopies of book dedications that others sent to Brodsky or to Ann Kjellberg. Other papers include personal notes that chiefly relate to daily activities and papers found in Brodsky's homes and offices (including some small printed artwork).
  - Certificates, diplomas and honorary medals, 1987 (Box 132, Folder 2968)
  - Certificates, diplomas and honorary medals, 1979-1988 (Box 133, Folder 2969-2976)
  - Drawings by Brodsky
    Drawings are sketches in ink or pencil unless otherwise indicated.
    - Sketch book with streetscapes and portraits, 1961? (Box 133, Folder 2977)
    - Scenes of a girl and a sailor by the ocean, from Zoia Tomashevskaia, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 2978)
    - "My past," "My present," and "My future", 1960s (Box 133, Folder 2979)
    - Man with lyre, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 2980)
    - Bard with lyre, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 2981)
    - Tomas Venclova, Era Korobiova and Brodsky, photocopy, 1972 May 24 (Box 133, Folder 2982)
    - Brodsky and Derek Walcott, 1988 October 4
    - "Self-portrait in Villa Borghese", undated (Box 133, Folder 2983)
    - "Earl of Ufliand", undated (Box 133, Folder 2984)
    - Other sketches, 1993, undated (Box 133, Folder 2985)
  - Calendars, date books and phone books, 1974-1995 (Box 134, Folder 2986-2995)
  - Calendars, date books and phone books, undated (Box 135, Folder 2996-3008)
    Includes notes on phone numbers and addresses, business cards, and Brodsky's letterhead from the University of Michigan.
  - Medical Papers, 1976-1991 (Box 136, Folder 3009-3020)
    Includes medical records, correspondence with medical providers, medical bills and notes related to Brodsky's health. Most of the material relates to Brodsky's heart condition.
  - Medical Papers, 1992-1995, undated (Box 137, Folder 3021-3028)
  - Financial Papers, 1972-1985 (Box 137, Folder 3029-3036)
    Includes bank statements, tax returns, receipts, cheques, airline tickets and material from real estate brokers.
  - Financial Papers, 1990-1993 (Box 138, Folder 3037-3048)
  - Financial Papers, 1994-2000, undated (Box 139, Folder 3049-3058)
    Includes bank statements, tax returns, receipts, cheques, airline tickets and material from real estate brokers. Also includes material related to the posthumous management of Brodsky's house in South Hadley.
  - Legal Papers, 1964-1976 (Box 139, Folder 3059-3069)
    Includes documentation of Brodsky's 1964 trial and 1972 immigration to the United States, employment and appearance contracts, and documentation of Brodsky's appeals on behalf of others in the Soviet Union, especially his parents.
  - Legal Papers, 1981-1995, undated (Box 140, Folder 3070-3092)
    Includes Brodsky's American passport and documentation of Brodsky's appeals on behalf of others in the Soviet Union, especially his parents
  - Inscriptions, 1987-1996 (Box 141, Folder 3093-3099)
    Consists of photocopies of Brodsky's inscriptions in presentation copies of his books. Inscriptions are addressed to Elena Chernyshova, Kim Dooley, Alan Kiepper, Judy Kjellberg, Helen Muchnic, Alan Myers, Rudolf Rossmann, Genrikh Shteinberg, and Masha [Vorobiov?].
  - Notes, 1973-1995, undated (Box 141, Folder 3100-3105)
    Notes that are not clearly related to writings are filed here. Includes autobiographical notes (circa 1973), drafts of Brodsky's curriculum vitae (1970s) and notes on Brodsky's emigration (undated).
  - Papers found in Mount Holyoke College office, undated (Box 141, Folder 3106)
    Consists of printed artwork and other papers apparently pinned on a bulletin board.
  - Papers found in South Hadley house, undated (Box 141, Folder 3107-3116)
    Consists of notes related to maintenance, business cards and ephemera, and artwork that had been on Brodsky's walls.
  - Papers found in Morton Street apartment, undated (Box 141, Folder 3117-3119)
    Consists of photographs, printed artwork and ephemera that had been taped to the door. Apparently these papers had been saved when Brodsky moved from Morton Street to Pierrepont Street.
  - Ann Kjellberg's notes on the contents of Brodsky's study at 22 Pierrepont Street, 1996 (Box 141, Folder 3120)
- Photographs, circa 1890-2001; Series VI; 7.3; (19 boxes)
  The Series is organized into five subseries: Joseph Brodsky, Family (including Brodsky as a child), Other People, Places and Other Photographs.
  Photographs span a wide range of styles, locations and subjects and document Brodsky's life from his childhood to his death, memorial and burial in 1996.
  Photographs of Joseph Brodsky comprise the bulk of the series and include professional portraits, snapshots and photographs with others. The settings for professional portraits include studios and Brodsky's homes and offices. Snapshots were taken by Brodsky and by his friends, including Veronique Schlitz and Masha Vorobiov. The heading Posthumous Photographs includes Brodsky's memorial, grave site, and South Hadley home at the time of Brodsky's death.
  Family Photographs date chiefly from Brodsky's childhood and there are very few photographs of his wife Maria Sozzani Brodsky and daughter Anna. There are no photographs of Brodsky's son Andrei Basmanov.
  Other People does not include Brodsky, although some of these snapshots may have been taken at events where Brodsky was present, or may have been taken by Brodsky.
  Places consists of photographs that do not depict known people, but were apparently taken while Brodsky was traveling, or to document his home and work environment.
  Other Photographs includes Brodsky's cats, art objects and unidentified subjects.
  - Joseph Brodsky
    - Professional Portraits
      Arranged alphabetically by name of photographer. Portraits by unidentified photographers are filed at the end of the listing.
      - Adlercreutz, Rolf, 1991
      - Alleva, Annalisa, 1989, undated (Box 142, Folder 3121-3122)
      - Arici, Graziano, undated (Box 142, Folder 3123)
      - Ask, Björn Larsson, undated
      - Boersma, Pieter, undated
      - Bohdziewicz, Anna Beata, undated (Box 142, Folder 3124)
      - Cook, Mariana, 1982 (Box 142, Folder 3125)
      - Crampton, Nancy, undated (Box 142, Folder 3126)
      - Czaplinski, Czeslaw, 1987, undated (Box 142, Folder 3127-3128)
      - Diepraam, Willem, undated (Box 142, Folder 3129)
      - Frey, Rudi, 1978
      - Fyodorova Makowska, Lyubov, undated (Box 142, Folder 3130)
        With Tatiana Tolstaia.
      - Gustavsson, Tobbe, undated (Box 142, Folder 3131)
      - Hunter, David, undated (Box 142, Folder 3132)
      - Hurn, David, circa 1993
        Includes a letter from Hurn to Brodsky.
      - Kalischer, Clemens, undated
      - Kopelev, Mark, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 3133)
      - Krementz, Jill, 1990s (Box 142, Folder 3134)
        With Derek Walcott, Adam Zagajewski and Mark Strand.
      - Lemhkin, Mikhail, 1968, 1988, undated (Box 142, Folder 3135-3137)
      - Liebling, Jerome, undated (Box 142, Folder 3138)
      - Lubianitsky, Leonid, undated (Box 142, Folder 3139)
        With Anatolii Naiman.
      - McGinnis, J. Richard, 1970s? (Box 142, Folder 3140-3141)
        With Victor Ehrlich and an unidentified person.
      - McKenna, Rollie, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 3142)
      - Pearson, Martha, 1979 (Box 142, Folder 3143)
        With Andrew Blane and an unidentified person.
      - Persson, Hasse, 1987 (Box 142, Folder 3144)
      - Rothfjell, Katarina, undated (Box 142, Folder 3145)
      - Schmalz, Julia, undated (Box 142, Folder 3146)
      - Sharymova, Natalia, undated (Box 142, Folder 3147-3148)
        Includes a photograph of Barry Rubin.
      - [Tomkins, Judy?], undated (Box 142, Folder 3149)
      - Vandermeer, Pieter, undated (Box 142, Folder 3150)
      - Victor, Thomas, undated (Box 142, Folder 3151)
      - Wise, Kelly, undated (Box 142, Folder 3152)
        With an unidentified person.
      - Unidentified photographers, 1970s-1990s (Box 142, Folder 3153-3161)
        Includes official document photographs.
    - Snapshots of Brodsky
      Snapshots of Brodsky are organized under the following headings: Places, Events, Posthumous Photographs and Other Snapshots.
      - Places
        Arranged alphabetically by country.
        - Austria, 1972 (Box 143, Folder 3162)
        - England, undated (Box 143, Folder 3163-3167)
        - France, 1976, 1978 (Box 143, Folder 3168-3169)
        - Germany, 1973 (Box 143, Folder 3170)
        - Greece
          See: Turkey
        - Italy, 1985, undated (Box 143, Folder 3171-3178)
        - Mexico, 1975 (Box 143, Folder 3179)
        - Poland, 1993 (Box 143, Folder 3180)
        - Russia, 1956-1972 (Box 143, Folder 3181-3186)
          For photographs of Brodsky as a child, see Family.
          Includes one photograph of Brodsky's trial in 1964.
        - Turkey, undated (Box 143, Folder 3187)
          Includes a few photographs in Greece.
        - United States
          - Amherst, Massachusetts, 1992 (Box 143, Folder 3188)
          - Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1973, undated (Box 143, Folder 3189-3193)
          - New York, New York, circa 1977-1986 (Box 143, Folder 3194-3195)
          - New York, New York, circa 1977-1986 (Box 144, Folder 3196-3199)
          - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1972 (Box 144, Folder 3200)
          - Poughkeepsie, New York, undated (Box 144, Folder 3201)
          - South Hadley, Massachusetts and Mount Holyoke College, circa 1982-1991 (Box 144, Folder 3202-3203)
      - Events
        - Poetry readings, lectures and book signing events, 1976-1993, undated (Box 144, Folder 3204-3210)
        - Honorary degree ceremonies, 1978-1988, undated (Box 144, Folder 3211-3219)
          Includes events at the University of Katowice, the University of Michigan, Yale University, Amherst College and Dartmouth College.
          Includes photographs with Mikhail Baryshnikov and Czesław Miłosz.
          Includes a letter from James J. Duderstadt.
        - Nobel Prize ceremonies and celebrations, 1987 (Box 144, Folder 3220-3230)
          Includes photographs with Giovanni Buttafava, Lev Losev, Margo Picken, Veronique Schiltz, Tomas Venclova, Kees Verheul, Masha Vorobiov and others.
        - Nobel Prize ceremonies and celebrations, 1987 (Box 145, Folder 3231-3237)
        - Unidentified ceremony, 1990s (Box 145, Folder 3238)
        - Brodsky's birthday parties, 1986-1995, undated (Box 146, Folder 3239-3263)
          Includes negatives.
      - Posthumous Photographs, 1997-2001 (Box 147, Folder 3264-3271)
        Includes photographs Brodsky's tomb, memorial, South Hadley home and preparation of Brodsky's archive by Ann Kjellberg.
      - Other Snapshots, 1974-1990s (Box 148, Folder 3272-3298)
    - Snapshots of Brodsky with Other People
      Arranged alphabetically by subject. Photographs with unidentified people are filed at the end of the listing.
      - Aaron, Jonathan and Rebecca, 1978, undated (Box 148, Folder 3299-3300)
      - Akely, Ann-Ellen, 1995 (Box 148, Folder 3301)
        Also with Ben Stoltz and Garrick Voskov.
      - Aleshkovskii, Iuz and Ira, undated (Box 148, Folder 3302-3303)
      - Bagby, Lew and Peg, undated (Box 148, Folder 3304)
      - Baryshnikov, Mikhail, undated (Box 149, Folder 3305-3307)
      - Blane, Andrew, undated (Box 149, Folder 3308-3309)
        Also with Vladimir Lunis.
      - Buttafava, Gianni, undated (Box 149, Folder 3310-3311)
        Also with Margo Picken and Veronique Schlitz.
      - Calasso, Roberto and Fleur, undated (Box 149, Folder 3312-3314)
      - [Cort?] Bianca, undated (Box 149, Folder 3315)
      - Efimov, Igor, undated (Box 149, Folder 3316)
        Also with Iakov Gordin and Anatolii Naiman.
      - Etkind, Efim and Masha, 1970s (Box 149, Folder 3317)
      - Filter, Susan, undated (Box 149, Folder 3318)
      - Gerritsen, Joke, undated (Box 149, Folder 3319)
      - Golyshev, Viktor, 1991 (Box 149, Folder 3320)
        Also with Liza Johnston and Andrew Blane.
      - Gross, Edith, undated (Box 149, Folder 3321)
      - [Hammberg?], Tia, 1998 (Box 149, Folder 3322)
      - Ivanov, Koma, 1987 (Box 149, Folder 3323)
      - Jangfeldt, Bengt, 1988 (Box 149, Folder 3324)
      - Jangfedlt, Sara, undated (Box 149, Folder 3325)
      - Kinnell, Galway, undated (Box 149, Folder 3326)
      - Kjellberg, Ann and Ray, undated (Box 149, Folder 3327)
      - Kline, George, 1974-1978, undated (Box 149, Folder 3328-3330)
      - Kushner, Aleksandr, undated (Box 149, Folder 3331-3332)
        Also with Viktor Golyshev.
      - Leonskaya, Lisa, undated (Box 149, Folder 3333)
        Also with Barry Rubin, Aleksandr Sumerkin and Marina Temkina.
      - Losev, Lev, 1980, undated (Box 149, Folder 3334)
      - Lunis, Vladimir, 1986, undated (Box 149, Folder 3335-3336)
      - Maksimov, Vladimir, undated (Box 149, Folder 3337)
        Also with an unidentified person, possibly Vladimir Maramzin.
      - Miłosz, Czesław, undated (Box 149, Folder 3338)
        Also with Derek Walcott and Octavio Paz.
      - Morgan, Robert, undated (Box 149, Folder 3339)
      - Morse, Rosemarie, undated (Box 149, Folder 3340)
      - Myers, Alan and Diana, circa 1974 (Box 149, Folder 3341)
        Also with Gianni Buttafava.
      - Naiman, Anatolii, 1960s-1990s (Box 149, Folder 3342-3343)
      - Paz, Octavio and Marie José, 1975, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 3344-3346)
        Also with Jonathan Aaron, Inez Kinnell, and Mark Strand.
      - Picken, Margo, 1975-1977, undated (Box 150, Folder 3347-3354)
      - Proffer, Carl and Ellendea, 1972-1984 (Box 150, Folder 3355-3356)
      - Ramer, Sam, undated (Box 150, Folder 3357-3358)
      - Reagan, Ronald and Nancy, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 3359)
      - Rein, Evgenii, 1966, 1988, undated (Box 150, Folder 3360-3362)
        Also with Aleksandr Kushner, Tatiana Tolstaia, Paul Graves, and Alisa Panova.
      - Rieff, David, undated (Box 150, Folder 3363)
        Also with Susan Sontag.
      - Rostropovich, Mstislav, 1970s (Box 150, Folder 3364)
        Also with Mikhail Baryshnikov, S. A. Galich and Galina Vishnevskaia.
      - Schiltz, Veronique, 1978-1980, undated (Box 151, Folder 3365-3384)
        Also with Jonathan Aaron, Diane Myers, Aleksandr Sumerkin and Peter Viereck.
      - Sontag, Susan, 1993, undated (Box 152, Folder 3385-3386)
        Also with Karen Kennerty, Jerzy Kozinsky and Roger Straus.
      - Stoltz, Ben
        See: Akely, Ann-Ellen
      - Strachan, Bill, undated (Box 152, Folder 3387)
      - Strand, Mark, undated (Box 152, Folder 3388)
      - Stroeve, Ada, 1977 (Box 152, Folder 3389-3390)
      - Struve, Nikita, undated (Box 152, Folder 3391)
      - Tranströmer, Tomas, 1988, undated (Box 152, Folder 3392)
      - Venclova, Tomas, 1972, 1977, undated (Box 152, Folder 3393-3394)
        Also with Ramunas Katilius and several unidentified people at the home of Efim Etkind in Russia, 1972.
      - Verheul, Kees, undated (Box 152, Folder 3395-3398)
        Also with Kees Smith and Ada Stroeve.
      - Vorobiov, Masha, 1973-1987, undated (Box 152, Folder 3399-3411)
        Also with Edith Gross, Susan Jacoby, Margo Picken, Veronique Schlitz, Kees Smith, and Kees Verheul.
      - Voskov, Garrick, 1987, undated (Box 153, Folder 3412-3415)
      - Walcott, Derek, 1983, undated (Box 153, Folder 3416-3422)
        Includes Jonathan Aaron, Michael di Capra, Jonathan Galassi, Seamus Heaney, Anthony Hecht, Sigrid Nama, David Rieff, Veronique Schlitz, Mark Strand, Roger Straus, Masha Vorobiov
      - White, Annamarie, Stephen and Chester, 1977 (Box 153, Folder 3423)
      - Unidentified people, 1977-1993, undated (Box 153, Folder 3424-3446)
  - Family
    - Brodskii, Aleksandr Ivanovich and Mariia Moiseevna Vol'pert-Brodskaia (Joseph Brodsky's parents), 1930s-1980s, undated (Box 154, Folder 3447-3454)
    - Brodsky, Joseph as a youth, 1944-1950s (Box 154, Folder 3455-3456)
      Also with members of Brodsky's family and unidentified friends.
    - Brodsky, Maria Sozzani and Anna, 1996 (Box 154, Folder 3457-3458)
    - Other family members, circa 1890-1980s (Box 154, Folder 3459-3462)
  - Other people
    Arranged alphabetically by name of subject.
    - Akhmatova, Anna, undated (Box 154, Folder 3463)
      Includes negative.
    - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), undated (Box 154, Folder 3464)
      Inscribed to Brodsky.
    - Baryshnikov, Mikhail, undated (Box 154, Folder 3465)
    - Gerasimov, Vladimir, undated (Box 154, Folder 3466)
    - Girolamo, Marcello, undated (Box 154, Folder 3467)
    - Golyshev, Viktor and family, undated (Box 154, Folder 3468-3470)
    - Gordin, Iakov, undated (Box 155, Folder 3471-3472)
      Includes Aleksandr Kushner, K. Ivanov and unidentified people at a conference in Russia
    - Hrabal, Bohumil, 1993 (Box 155, Folder 3473)
    - Jangfeldt, Bengt, undated (Box 155, Folder 3474)
    - Jangfeldt, Sara, 1989, undated (Box 155, Folder 3475)
    - Kasatkina, Lena, 1995 (Box 155, Folder 3476)
      With Petr Vail.
    - Katilius, Ramunas and Elmira, undated (Box 155, Folder 3477)
    - Kjellberg, Ann and Sara, 2001, undated (Box 155, Folder 3478-3479)
    - Korobova, Era, undated (Box 155, Folder 3480)
    - Kushner, Aleksandr, undated (Box 155, Folder 3481)
    - Leonskaya, L., undated (Box 155, Folder 3482)
    - Losev, Lev, undated (Box 155, Folder 3483)
      With Iuz Aleshkovskii, Sergei Dovlatov, Garrick Voskov and unidentified people.
    - Mandelshtam, Nadezhda, 1967 (Box 155, Folder 3484)
    - Miłosz, Czesław, undated (Box 155, Folder 3485)
    - [Muldoon, Paul?], undated (Box 155, Folder 3486)
    - Naiman, Anatolii, undated (Box 155, Folder 3487)
    - Picken, Margo, undated (Box 155, Folder 3488)
    - Rein, Evgenii, 1979-1993, undated (Box 155, Folder 3489-3494)
      With L. Jangfeldt and Aleksandr Kushner.
    - Rostropovich, Mstislav, undated (Box 155, Folder 3495)
    - Schlitz, Veronique, undated (Box 155, Folder 3496-3497)
    - Spender, Stephen, undated (Box 155, Folder 3498)
    - Tomashovskii, Boris, undated (Box 155, Folder 3499)
    - Tsvetaeva, Marina, undated (Box 155, Folder 3500)
      Photocopy of a photograph that hung over Brodsky's fireplace.
    - Ufliand, Vladimir, undated (Box 155, Folder 3501-3502)
      With ____ Eremin and Vladimir Gerasimov.
    - Venclova, Tomas, 1995, undated (Box 155, Folder 3503-3506)
    - Verheul, Kees, undated (Box 155, Folder 3507)
      With Kees Smith.
    - Vorobiov, Masha, 1975-1987, undated (Box 155, Folder 3508-3514)
      With Edith Gross.
    - Voskov, Garrick, undated (Box 155, Folder 3515-3516)
      With Lev Losev.
    - Wolcott, Derek, undated (Box 155, Folder 3517)